Dawn Savidge

linkedin.com/in/dawnsavidge

Summary

Proven Leadership. Team oriented. Driving rapid growth by creating systems to drive internal efficiencies, improve team workflows, and communication plans that inspire change. Broad experience including market research and analysis, project management, communication, public relations, and leading teams with proven success in B2B, B2C, and B2G sectors. Demonstrated ability in developing marketing strategies to increase brand awareness and instigate growth through traditional and digital communication channels. High achieving individual with high personal standards of integrity and excellence. 20 years business experience.

Selected Professional Experience

POLYWOOD Outdoor Furniture Digital Content Manager

12/2019 - Present

POLYWOOD Outdoor Furniture is a high growth company celebrating 30 years of success. The company launched in 1980 to find a use for recycled plastic. Today it incorporates ocean-bound and landfill-bound plastic into its beautiful outdoor furniture that will last a life-time. With YoY growth moving from ~20% to 50% to the over ~200%, in the past three years, my contributions have been in:

- Creating an Influencer Marketing program to increase brand awareness through systematically vetting each Influencer, determining the value of each engagement, setting goals, and determining the KPIs and reporting to track each collaboration
- Project Management of the company's first crowdfunding campaign for a new product launch with just 4 weeks to prepare and including a team of ~15 people, reaching 80% funding and driving new traffic to the direct ecommerce website
- Implementing agile project management and workflow system with Teamwork software for the Creative Marketing Team to give visibility of tasks between 5 different departments, reducing missed and late work by 100%
- Initiating internal Public Relations processes including Twitter, LinkedIn, and Communication procedures internally and with PR Agency for over 70 appearances in media publications including Forbes, Yahoo, and many others
- Establishing increased cadence of content marketing plan that increased email subscriptions by 2x while concurrently decreasing unsubscribes, increasing Instagram followers by 37% in 6 months, as well as launching new Pinterest initiative

Go with Friends is a social start-up currently in the development phase. Following is a brief list of the efforts I have led toward launching this start-up:

- Market research and competitive analysis, preliminary design, UX, and prototyping
- Assessing software and platforms, establishing information systems & communication
 procedures, detailing go-to-market plan including SEO strategy, crowdfunding strategy, initiating
 social media presence, and building website in WordPress initial landing page coming soon
- Writing RFQ, workflow layout, designing internship, and programmer hiring process

Colortech, Morristown, Tennessee *Marketing Analyst*

05/2017 - 11/2018

Colortech is a leading North American supplier of color and additive concentrates for the plastics industry. Sales increased ~10% in 2017 in this mature industry. As the Marketing Analyst, I launched a new marketing department to support the sales team of 18, working closely with R&D, Technical Team, IT, and Sales.

- Researching markets & developing lead qualification process to broaden customer base and increase sales
- Building brand awareness through creation of sales literature, product video, customer presentations, social media marketing, press releases, and launching new website rebuild and SEO strategy
- Project Management of custom pricing software to improve efficiency by 50%
- Pricing ~1500 custom products, working with procurement, R&D, and inside sales team
- Sustainability Team member and Corporate Representative with the Plastics Industry Association

TEVET, LLC, Mosheim, Tennessee Director of Marketing

03/2016 - 02/2017

TEVET is an award-winning small business and the top-selling reseller of the most innovative test and measurement equipment brands to the aerospace & defense industry. Sales on existing products grew by ~38% in 2016 to nearly \$200M and we set the stage to expand into new products. As Marketing Director, it was my responsibility to propel the company forward in three of its top four initiatives:

- Overseeing website rebuild & developing SEO and web maintenance strategy
- KPI development, tracking and reporting metrics to CEO and VP of Sales
- Project Management of on-time Punch-Out Catalog (e-commerce) instance
- Launching marketing automation system (Pardot) & syncing with NetSuite CRM while managing detailed segmentation and managing segmented email content creation
- Build Relationships with national suppliers, gaining 50% increase in co-marketing funds
- Developing and implementing social media marketing and LinkedIn Sales Navigator strategy
- Managing 20 annual trade shows, marketing budget, technical email content and calendar

Jarden Zinc Products, Greeneville, Tennessee Marketing Specialist

09/2013 - 02/2016

Jarden Zinc Products is the largest North American producer of solid zinc strip, zinc-based products, and the only producer of the U.S. penny blank. As Marketing Specialist, I had responsibility for managing all aspects of marketing activities for the 20-member sales team supporting three global product lines. These efforts contributed to a 15% annual growth rate of new and existing product lines resulting in ~\$180M in annual revenue in 2015. As a valued team member, my projects included:

- Market research and insights for potential new product development
- Spearheading creation of product names, literature, product video, educational presentation and process, and website rebuild with Google Analytics to increase product awareness
- Transforming sample order process to improve quality, efficiency, cost, accuracy, and ensure ample stock on hand
- Planning national sales events for newly launched architectural products
- Creating monthly sales report for VP Sales & Marketing to identify opportunities
- Working with collaborative teams to develop white papers, technical documents, and corporate presentations for global trade shows leading to global partnerships

Ball State University – Miller College of Business, Muncie, Indiana Graduate Research Fellow

08/2011 - 12/2012

The Miller College of Business at Ball State University is an AACSB accredited school serving nearly 3,200 graduate and undergraduate students. As the Graduate Research Fellow, my responsibility was to support the Dean and Associate Dean in the following:

- Research, statistical analysis, and writing academic paper on effects of Right-to-Work laws
- Collecting and compiling data on all faculty and their academic research for accreditation
- · Compiling aspirant list of business colleges

Century 21, Scheetz REALTOR® and Licensed Assistant

06/2001 - 06/2003

Century 21, Scheetz is a prominent Real Estate Brokerage in a highly sought-after county north of Indianapolis. During this time, I sold residential real estate as well as assisted Top Agent, Edna Brinker, now retired:

- Statistical analysis of Market and creating monthly newsletter
- Selling residential real estate

Master's Project

Mursix Corporation, Yorktown, Indiana Market Research Project Lead

08/2012 - 12/2012

Mursix Corporation is a state-of-the-art engineering and manufacturing company of electrical components. As a result of this research project, they expanded their product offerings to include the alternative energy sector. As the team lead of four graduate students, I embarked on the following:

- Project Management, determining knowledge base, and directing collection of data to assess market potential of electric vehicles, charging stations, and grid storage
- Analyzing data to determine market trends and growth potential & presenting findings and recommendations to the executive staff leading to new partnerships and market offerings

Education

Eleven Fifty Academy, May 2021

Web Development

Master of Business Administration, 2012

Ball State University, Muncie, Indiana

- Graduate Merit Fellowship
- Certificate of High Achievement at the Master's Level

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration: Entrepreneurship, 2011

Ball State University, Muncie, Indiana

- Receiving highest GPA in top ten ranked entrepreneurship program
- Scoring in 95 percentile of graduating business students
- Teaching supplemental statistics course achieving highest attendance of any SI course on record
- Beta Gamma Sigma Honor Society
- Miller College of Business Top Scholars
- President, Collegiate Entrepreneurs' Organization Ball State Chapter
- Founding Director Ghostly Gallop 5k Fundraiser
- National Sales Quarterfinalist National Collegiate Sales Competition

Certificate Computer Programming, 1984

Computer Learning Center, Springfield, Virginia

Microsoft Project 1, 2016

BCTI, Johnson City, Tennessee

Content Marketing Certificate, 2019

HubSpot Academy

SEO Fundamentals, 2019 - 2020

Yoast, LinkedIn Learning, Backlinko, Moz

Google Analytics Certificate, 2019

Google Analytics Academy

Social Media Analytics, 2020

Quintly Academy

Advanced Twitter Training, 2020

The Content Factory